A Guide to the Clifton A. Woodrum papers, 1894-1954
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Clifton A. Woodrum papers, 1894-1954
The Library of Virginia
51581
4.475 cu. ft. and 12 boxes
Clifton A. Woodrum
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Robert H. Woodrum of Stone Mountain, Georgia.
Biographical Information
Clifton Alexander Woodrum was born 27 April 1887 in Roanoke, Virginia, to Robert H. Woodrum (1852-1912) and Anna T. Musgrove Woodrum (1861-1939). He attended Roanoke public schools. Woodrum worked as a soda-jerk in a pharmacy and studied pharmacy at the same time, becoming a licensed pharmacist. While a pharmacist, Woodrum studied law at Washington and Lee University, received his law degree, and was licensed to practice 19 June 1908. He practiced law in Roanoke and was elected Commonwealth's Attorney 1917. In August 1919 he was unanimously appointed to the bench of the Roanoke hustings court. Woodrum was elected to Congress from the Sixth Virginia Congressional District and served until he resigned in December 1945. After his resignation, he served as president of the American Plant Food Council, Inc. Woodrum married Martha Lena Hancock (1874?-1969) on 26 December 1905, and they had two children. Woodrum died 6 October 1950 in Washington D.C. He was buried in Fairview Cemeter in Roanoke, Virginia.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1894-1954, of Clifton A. Woodrum (1887-1950) of Roanoke, Virginia, consisting of bulletins, cards, clippings, correspondence, diaries, legal papers, magazines, photographs, programs, reports, speeches, ephemera, and other papers detailing Woodrum's career as a United States Congressman and president of the American Plant Food Council, Inc. Collection also covers Woodrum's activities as a singer and in fraternal organizations. Also includes papers relating to his wife Lena Hancock Woodrum (1874-1969) and his children, Clifton Woodrum, Jr. (1910-1959) and Martha Ann Woodrum (Zillhardt) (1916-2002).
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Correspondence and general papers, 1894-1950
Series II: Elections, 1922, 1938, 1940
Series III: Congress, 1921-1951
Series IV: American Plant Food Council, 1947, 1950
Series V: Speeches, 1915-1950
Series VI: Publications, 1939-1950
Series VII: Clippings, 1900-1954
Series VIII: Photographs
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Clifton A. Woodrum correspondence, 15-30 December 1938 (LVA accession 42517).
Contents List
- Series I: Correspondence and general papers, 1894-1950., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1)
  Correspondence and general papers, 1894-1950, consisting of advertisements, bulletins, cards, certificates, checks, clippings, diaries, invitations, letters, menus, poems, postcards, programs, receipts, recipes, report cards, resolutions, speeches, telegrams, tickets, visiting cards, and other papers concerning Clifton A. Woodrum's personal and social life, as well as his professional career as a lawyer and congressman. Papers also cover the personal and social lives of his wife Lena Woodrum and children. Papers also include information on the education of Clifton A. Woodrum, Jr., and Martha Ann Woodrum.
  - Correspondence and general papers, 1900[?], 1905-1906, 1912-1913, 1918. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and general papers, 1921-1928, 192[-]. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and general papers, 1933-1936, 1939. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and general papers, 1941-1944. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and general papers, 1945. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence and general papers, August-September 1946. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and general papers, October-November 1946. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence and general papers, 1947-1950. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence and general papers, undated. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Memorials on the death of Clifton A. Woodrum, October 1950. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Certificates, 1907-1948. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Church bulletins (including services in which Woodrum sang), 1926-1929, 1946. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Programs, 1925-1930, 1950, undated. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Religous addresses, remarks, etc., 1925, undated. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Inauguration ceremony pass and president and party menus, 4 March 1933, 19-20 October 1934. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Fraternal organizations, 1921, 1926-1929, 1946, undated. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Ora M. Jacobs papers, re: property purchase in Florida, 1922. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Calling cards, 1925-1926, undated. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Notes and miscellaneous papers. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Lena Hancock [Woodrum] diary, 1894-1897. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - (Martha) Lena Hancock [Woodrum] calling cards and papers. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Clifton A. Woodrum, Jr., papers, 1921-1931, undated. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Martha Ann Woodrum papers, 1919-1927. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Recipes, menus,store ads, etc. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Poems. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Cards, invitations, etc. (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Series II: Elections, 1922, 1938, 1940., Extent: 1 box. (Box 2)
  Elections, 1922, 1938, 1940, consists of broadsides, business cards, clippings, judicial records, letters, lists, scrapbooks, signs, speeches, telegrams, and other papers concerning Clifton A. Woodrum's primary race for the congressional Democratic nomination in 1922, and his general election campaigns for Congress in 1938 and 1940.
  - Scrapbook, 1922. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1922. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - General papers, 1922. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Address of Harvey Hall, 1 July 1922. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Speech of Judge R. C. Jackson, 1 July 1922. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Speech of W. H. Colhoun, 1 July 1922. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - James P. Woods speech, 1922. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Speech for James P. Woods, 1922. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Statements regarding C. A. Woodrum, 1922. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Commonwealth of Virginia vs. C. M. Truax, 1922. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Papers regarding signing of orders in the Roanoke Hustings Court, 1922. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Scrapbook, 1938. (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1940. (Box 2)
- Series III: Congress, 1921-1951., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 3-4)
  Congress, 1921-1951, includes biographies, correspondence, legislation, reports, speeches, and other papers containing speeches and remarks given by Clifton A. Woodrum while serving in Congress, as well as remarks by others upon his retirement in 1945 and upon his death in 1950. Some of the remarks and reports are published in the Congressional Record. Series also includes papers detailing problems of three of Woodrum's constituents.
  - Congressional Record, 11 October 1921. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - A brief in favor of the Purnell Bill (agricultural experiment stations), 1921. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Congressional Record regarding the U.S. Army Band, 11 February 1926. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Clifton A. Woodrum minority report on the Sesquicentennial in Philadelphia, 8 February 1926. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Congressional Record, minority view on H.R. 6518, the Welch Bill (government employee salaries), 27 April 1928. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Bill, Fiscal Year 1940--Clifton A. Woodrum America Prepares for Peace, 16 January 1940. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Congressional Record, extension of remarks of Clifton A. Woodrum on national defense, 30 August 1940. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Congressional Record, remarks of Clifton A. Woodrum--Our Sky Pilot G. S. M.,, 16 April 1941. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Congressional Record, Clifton A Woodrum unity speech, 17 February 1942. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Congressional Record, Clifton A. Woodrum--But One Objective and that Objective Is to Win the War, 17 February 1942. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Congressional Record, Clifton A. Woodrum--The State of the Union, 16 March 1942. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Speech of John E. Rankin (D-Mississippi) on the Fair Employment Practice Committee, 26 May 1944. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Foreign Economic Administration Appropriation Bill, 1945--hearing befor the sub-committee of the Committee of Appropriations (U.S. Senate), 8 June 1944. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Post-War Military Policy--1st Report of the House Select Committee on Post-War Military Policy, 15 June 1944. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Where Local Government Stands Today--extension of remarks of Clifton A. Woodrum, 20 September 1944. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Reduction of Nonessential Federal Expenditures--Additional Report of the Joint Committee on Reduction of Nonessential Federal Expenditures, 1944. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Congressional Record--Clifton A. Woodrum, The End of the Road on the death of Franklin D. Roosevelt, 17 April 1945. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Congressional Record--Retirement of Clifton A. Woodrum (pp. 12370 ff), 17 December 1945. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Twenty-Three Years of Service in Congress--retirement of Clifton A. Woodrum, 17 December 1945. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Clifton A. Woodrum biography, 1945. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - A Selection of Editorial and News Comments upon the Occasion when Clifton A. Woodrum Announced His Intensions of Retiring from Congress, 1945. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Congressional Record, 12 February 1948. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Congressional Quarterly, 25 June, 17 August 1958. (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Department of Commerce Appropriations Bill for 1950--specifically aviation (see index, p. 732), 1949. (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Congressional Record--death of Clifton A. Woodrum (pp. 16569-16572), 11 December 1950. (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Congressional Record--death of Clifton A. Woodrum (p. A8476), 17 January 1951. (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Britton Douglas Luck Gowens claim, February-March 1923. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Britton Douglas Luck Gowens claim, April 1923. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Britton Douglas Luck Gowens claim, May-July 1923. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Britton Douglas Luck Gowens claim, November 1923-January 1924. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Britton Douglas Luck Gowens claim, April-May, August 1924. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Britton Douglas Luck Gowens claim, March 1927, undated. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Sidney Lanier Smith court-martial [MATERIAL IS RESTRICTED UNTIL 31 DECEMBER 2023], 1923-1924. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Joseph Davidson tax assessment, 1924. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Hamilton Fish papers, 1941. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Blank stationery. (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Series IV: American Plant Food Council, 1947, 1950., Extent: 1 box. (Box 4)
  American Plant Food Council, 1947, 1950, contains statements, 1947, by fertilizer businesses to a House sub-committee on fertilizer; a statement, 1950, by Clifton A. Woodrum, American Plant Food Council president on the Federal Trade Commission report on fertilizer; and stationery.
  - Statements of Horace M. Albright (Unite States Potash Company, Inc.), Ralph B. Douglass (Smith-Douglass Company), and Herbert H. Meyers (Virginia-Carolina Chemical Corporation) to the Sub-Committee of the House Agricultural Committee on Fertilizer, 31 January 1947. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - The Federal Trade Commission Report on the Fertilizer Industry--(tentative) statement by Clifton A. Woodrum, president of the American Plant Food Council, 1950. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Blank stationery. (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Series V: Speeches, 1915-1950., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 4-5)
  Speeches, 1915-1950, delivered by Clifton A. Woodrum to fraternal orders, civic groups, women's groups, and other organizations, as well as in the House of Representatives and to the American Plant Food Council. Topics include politics, economy, civics, fraternal orders, and agriculture.
  - Memorial address to the Roanoke Aerial Eagles, 31 October 1915. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Memorial address--National Home, Benevolent and Protective Order of the Elks, December 1915. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Address delivered at Christiansburg, Virginia, 4 July 1917. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Elks Golden Jubilee, 16 February 1918. (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Woodmen of the World speech, 191[-]. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Freemasons speech, 191[-]. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Flag Day--Roanoke Lodge of the Benevolent and Protective Order of the Elks, 13 June 1920. (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Address for Bristol Kiwanis Club Governor's Night Celebration, 29 December 1921. (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - The Vision Glorious--address at Washington and Lee University, 8 March 1922. (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Flag Day speech--Lynchburg Elks, 14 June 1925. (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Labor Record of Alfred E. Smith--radio address, 4 October 1928. (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - 4th of July speech to the Kiwanis Club, 1 July 1931. (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - On the Question of the Repeal of the 18th Amendment--radio address, 25 September [1933]. (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - National Defense--address to teh 38th Virginia State Conference, Daughters of the American Revolution, 20 March 1934. (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Address to the Kiwanis Club, 14 June 1934. (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Address to the Virginia Bankers Association, Danville, Virginia, 14 May 1938. (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Public Spending--radio address, 22 May 1939. (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Recent Economic Trends--Daughters of the American Revolution, 193[-]. (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Worthy Public Aims--Allegheny County (Pa.) Construction Associates, 23 January 1941. (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - State of the Union--radio address, Blue Network of NBC, 16 March 1942. (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Address to the Kiwanis Clubs of Richmond, 6 September 1944. (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Address to the Virginia League of Municipalities (with accompanying doccument), 25 September 1944. (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Address on WDBJ Radio, Roanoke, 25 October [1944]. (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Address in Indianapolis,Indiana, concerning the end of World War II, 22 February 1945. (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Some of Our Post-War Problems--Norfolk Rotary Club, 29 May 1945. (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - A portion of remarks of Mr. Woodrum, 17 December 1945. (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Mother Earth--Clifton A. Woodrum at Hot Springs, Virginia, with extension of remarks of J. Lindsey Almond, 24, 29 June 1946. (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Country Journal" interview with Don Lerch, 1 February 1947. (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Our Land and Its Care--Clifton A. Woodrum, President of the American Plant Food Council, to the Jr. Chamber of Commerce, Roanoke, 25 February 1947. (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Outlook for 1948"--address of Clifton A. Woodrum at the annual banquet of the Norfolk-Portsmouth Chapter of the American Institute of Banking, 17 January 1948. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Address of Clifton A. Woodrum at the Graduation Exercises [of] Madidon [sic] [Madison] College, 6 June 1949. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Teamed for Defense--Armed Forces Day at Virginia Polytechnic Institute, 20 May 1950. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Address of Clifton A. Woodrum, President of the American Plant Food Council, at the fifth annual meeting of the Council at the Homestead, Hot Springs, Virginia, 30 June 1950. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Speech (first page missing), undated. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Early History of Andrew Taylor Still, undated. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Material used in speeches, 1947, undated. (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Series VI: Publications, 1939-1950., Extent: 1 box. (Box 5)
  Publications, 1939-1950, consists of booklets, magazines, and newsletters relating to politics, economy, and the American Plant Food Council.
  - Business Week, 24 June 1939. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Cliff Woodrum Says newsletter, 6 July, 3 October 1940. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - The Commonwealth, April 1949. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Country Club News newsletter (Roanoke), July 1945. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Democracy's Salvation Depends Upon Adopting a Competitively Produced Money System, 1944. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Alabama Today and Tomorrow newsletter (Alabama State Chamber of Commerce), November 1945. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Our Land and Its Care, 1947. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - American Plant Food Council Journal, January-February-March 1947, April-May-June 1950. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - United States News, 19 April 1940, 30 June 1944. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Life, 20 March 1930. (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Series VII: Clippings, 1900-1954., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 5-6)
  Clippings, 1922-1954, hightlight Clifton A. Woodrum's political career, his singing appearances, and his social life. Clippings also cover the arrival of Admiral Richard E. Byrd in New York in 1926 and the dedication of Woodrum Field in Roanoke in 1941. Clippings also concern Clifton A. Woodrum, Jr., and Martha Ann Woodrum, as well as general news.
  - Election, 1922. (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Election, 1924. (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Election, 1926. (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Election, 1928. (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Politics, 1924, 1926. (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Politics, 1928-1929. (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Politics, 1931-1933. (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Politics, 1934. (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Politics, 1935. (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Politics, 1936-1938, 193[-]. (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Politics, 1941-1946, 1948. (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Politics--elections, 1948. (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Politics, undated. (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Clifton A. Woodrum speaking engagements, 1926-1930, undated. (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Clifton A. Woodrum appearances as a singer, 1926-1928, undated. (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Maryland school oratory competition, 1926. (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Wright Pavilion cornerstone ceremony, 1926. (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Mother's Day observance, 9 May 1926. (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Admiral Richard E. Byrd's arrival in New York, June 1926. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Medical unit in Roanoke for veterans, 1926. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Federal building and Roanoke post office, 1926, 1929. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Dedication of Woodrum Field, October 1941. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Clifton A. Woodrum general clippings (see also box 12, folder 1--oversized materials), 1926-1950. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Clifton A. Woodrum death and funeral, 1950. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Clifton A. Woodrum, Jr., 1926-1933. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Clifton A. Woodrum, Jr., wedding and family, 1935-1945. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Clifton A. Woodrum, Jr., World War II, 1940-1948. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Clifton Woodrum, Jr., 1945-1950. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Martha Ann Woodrum, 1926-1947. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Social items concerning Clifton A. Woodrum and family, 1926-1930, 1935. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - General social, 1900, 1926-1954. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - General, no date. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Masons, Pythians, Kiwanis, and other associations, 1922-1926, undated. (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Marriages, 1936. (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Sports related, undated. (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Recipes, undated. (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Poems, undated. (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Series VIII: Photographs., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 6-8)
  Photographs of Clifton A. Woodrum and his family. Also contains photographs reflecting Woodrum's congressional career and his tenure as president of the American Plant Food Council. Also includes photographs of family friends and political figures.
  - Photographs, Clifton A. Woodrum portraits (see also box 12, folder 3--oversized materials). (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Photographs, Clifton A. Woodrum portraits (see also box 12, folder 3--oversized materials). (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Photographs, Clifton A. Woodrum portraits (see also box 12, folder 3--oversized materials). (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Photographs, Clifton A. Woodrum--American Plant Food Council (see box 5, folder 15 also), 1947. (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Photographs, Clifton A. Woodrum--American Plant Food Council (see box 5, folder 15 also), 1950. (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Photographs, lodge portrait dedication and lodge dinner. (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Photographs, Clifton A. Woodrum--general. (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Photographs, Clifton A. Woodrum--general. (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Photographs, Clifton A. Woodrum--general. (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Photographs, Clifton A. Woodrum and Lena Woodrum. (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Photographs, Lena Woodrum. (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Photographs, Clifton A. Woodrum, Jr., as a child. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, Clifton A. Woodrum, Jr.--Virginia Military Institute. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, Clifton A. Woodrum, Jr.--general. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, Clifton A. Woodrum, Jr.--general. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, Martha Ann Woodrum--portraits. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, Martha Ann Woodrum--portraits. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, Martha Ann Woodrum--portraits. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, Martha Ann Woodrum as a child. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, Martha Ann Woodrum--airplanes. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Photographs, Martha Ann Woodrum--fashion. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Photographs, Martha Ann Woodrum--general. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Photographs, Martha Ann Woodrum--general. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Photographs, Martha Ann Woodrum[?]--air show. (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Photographs, Martha Ann Woodrum[?]--air show and poolside. (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Photographs, Martha Ann Woodrum[?]--general. (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Photographs, Woodrum family. (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Photographs, Woodrum family and friends--Roanoke Photo Finishing Company, 1937-1944. (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Photographs, autographed photographs to Clifton A. Woodrum (see also box 12, folder 4--oversized materials). (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Photographs, general--children. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, general--men (see also box 12, folder 4--oversized materials). (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, general--women (see also box 12, folder 4--oversized materials). (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, general--groups. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Photographs--Los Angeles. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Photographs--houses and objects. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Roanoke at night. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Snowmass Valley, Colorado. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Dedication of Woodrum Field, Roanoke. (Box 12)
- Series IX: Scrapbooks., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 8-10)
  Scrapbooks contain clippings and photographs of Clifton A. Woodrum and his family, as well as highlighting his political career. Some scrapbooks are currently unavailable due to conservation needs.
  - Scrapbook, 1934-1942. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook, 1940-1942, scrapbook runs in reverse chronological order. Part I--17 March 1942-3 June 1941. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook, 1940-1942, scrapbook runs in reverse chronological order. Part II--31 May 1941-3 December 1940. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Scrapbook, 1940-1942, scrapbook runs in reverse chronological order--26 April 1942-1 December 1940. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook--MAAF Foto, Italy, 1945. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Woodrum family scrapbook, 1919-ca. 1928. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Woodrum family scrapbook, ca. 1936-ca. 1938. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Woodrum family photo album, ca. 1910-ca. 1949. (Box 9)
  - Annie T. Woodrum scrapbook, 1939. (Box 10)
- Series X: Ephemera., Extent: 1 box. (Box 11)
  Ephemera contains items owned by Clifton A. Woodrum.
  - Victory Songs (hymns). (Box 11)
  - New Testament. (Box 11)
  - Vest Pocket Congressional Directory, 1939. (Box 11)
  - Roll of film. (Box 11)
  - Address block. (Box 11)
  - Hair of Clifton Woodrum, Jr., and hair of an unidentified individual. (Box 11)
  - Spoons and letter openers. (Box 11)
  - Seals. (Box 11)
  - Compass. (Box 11)
  - Bracelet. (Box 11)
  - Campaign fans (located in box 12, oversized material). (Box 11)